doing all he can to to to cause habit
Lord please
Speak Lord
and may your voice come through
loud and clear is my prayer in Jesus
name amen amen
all right
um
so
let's go ahead
and look at our first verse we're going
to go to the screen
and um
let's look at our first verse which is
found in Isaiah
chapter 5. and verse 20. Isaiah chapter
and verse 20. let's see if we can get
that up on the screen
[Music]
Isaiah chapter 5 and verse 20. the Bible
says woe unto them that call evil good
and good evil that put Darkness for
light and light for Darkness
that put bitter for sweets and sweet for
bitter woe unto them that are wise in
their own eyes and Prudence in their own
sight woe unto them that are Mighty to
drink wine and Men of strength to mingle
strong drink which justify the wicked
for reward and take away the
righteousness of the righteous from him
um
this text is pointing out the fact that
there is a danger in calling evil good
and good evil
we we we
endanger ourselves if we call something
that God has blessed cursed or something
that God has cursed
blessed
are y'all with me so far
I'm sending this Foundation because we
need to understand that if God has
blessed the Sabbath and we are calling
it cursed Isaiah chapter 5
is a condemnation against us
however if God has cursed the Sabbath
and we are calling it blessed
we run the same risk we run this we are
under the same condemnation
so we want to make sure that we're not
calling that which is blessed cursed and
we're not calling that which is Curse
blessed put a one in the chat if you
follow me so far if we are good so far
so with that in mind I I want to go to
our next text because what we're going
to do here is we're going to study the
subject of the Sabbath first through the
Old Testament
then through the gospels Matthew Mark
Luke and John and then through the New
Testament early church and we're talking
about three different phases in the
scripture so first we're staying in the
Old Testament second we're going to go
to the books of Matthew Mark Luke and
John and study the Sabbath in that
context and then finally we're going to
study the book study the Sabbath from
the book of Acts all the way to the Book
of Revelation all right we're going to
be very methodical with this study okay
so let's go ahead and and look first at
uh uh the new the Old Testament Genesis
chapter two let's see if we can get this
up on the screen Genesis chapter 2
beginning with verse one Genesis chapter
2 verse one the Bible says thus the
heavens and the Earth were finished and
all the hosts of them and on the seventh
day God ended his work which he had made
and he rested on the seventh day from
all his work which he had made and God
blessed the seventh day and Sanctified
it because that in it he had rested from
all his work which God created and made
so the first thing I want you to see
here is the fact that God rested God
Sabbath
and we're told that the reason that the
Sabbath is blessed is because
God rested
are y'all with me
on that day
put a one in the chat if y'all follow me
so far
the reason the Sabbath is blessed
has to do with something God did way
back there at creation
and and I would say this beloved that
that in order for
the the the the the
Sabbath itself to no longer be blessed
we would have to go back into history
and erase the events
that made it blessed
my birthday is September 23rd
in order for September 23rd to no longer
be my birthday we would have to go back
in time
and change the event of me being born on
September 23rd
are y'all with me so far
the Reason God blessed the Sabbath
according to the Old Testament is
because of what he did on that day
all right so far so good that's the Old
Testament and I want you to note
something else here after God created
man on day six listen carefully to this
the first gift that God gives men we're
talking about you know
Christmas season everybody's into
getting gifts the first gift that God
gives man notice with me
According To Jesus watch this in the
Book of Mark chapter 2
and verse 27.
the Bible says that the Sabbath was made
for man
the Sabbath was made for men it goes on
to say and not matter Sabbath therefore
the son of man is Lord also the Sabbath
but all I want you to focus on right now
is this very simple yet profound truth
that God not only blessed the Sabbath by
resting on it but he gave it to man that
was one of the first things man received
God said Adam Eve I made this day
for you it's a gift for you
now beloved what does the polite thing
to do when someone gives you a gift when
someone makes a gift for you what is the
polite thing to do the part I think the
kind things the nice thing to do the
right thing to do is receive the gift
are y'all with me
God makes a Sabbath as a gift for man
and now now please know how I'm gonna
I'm gonna say this
the Sabbath was mad was God's gift to
man after the creation of man
the Sabbath was the first thing God
gives to man the first gift God gives to
man after creation it is a sign of the
creation of the world it is a sign of
the creation of man
if we got that point we're we're good to
go and I don't think anyone would argue
this point at least at this point I want
you to notice a second point though
and it is this Not only was the Sabbath
giving
as a symbol of the creation of man as a
gift to man after his creation but the
Sabbath was given again
at a much later time
you'll remember
by the way by the way let me pause for a
second
does the Sabbath refer
to the whole world
put a one in the chat if you would say
yes
God made the Sabbath because he created
the world in six days so if you would
say yes the Sabbath pertains to the
whole world put a one in the chat
put a one in the chat and and what I
want you to understand because you
should put a one in the chat because the
the Sabbath involves the whole world
what I want you to understand about this
point I'm about to make is very simple
that the Sabbath is global it is a
global thing
it is a universal thing it was not a
local thing
the Sabbath literally involves the
entire world and all of creation
does that make sense
all right so that was Point number one
point number two we're gonna go back to
our screen
and I want you to notice that the
Sabbath is also the first gift God gives
to man after
man's Redemption
okay
what do you mean Pastor you remember
that that the children of Israel are in
Egyptian captivity for 400 years and
then according to Exodus 19
verse 4 after God leads them out of
bondage after God leads them out of
captivity
the Bible says Nexus 19 verse 4 you have
seen what I did unto the Egyptians and
how I bear You On Eagle's Wings and
brought you unto myself
all right let's pause for a second
did God bring the children of Israel
unto himself
did the children of Israel come unto him
yes or no
obviously the answer is yes God says I
brought you unto myself so the children
of Israel were brought unto God they
came unto him that's Exodus chapter 19.
and after he leads them out of captivity
after he leads them out of their bondage
Exodus 19 God says I delivered you unto
myself notice what he gives them in
Exodus chapter 20. let's go back to the
screen
and The Exodus 20.
you'll see God giving the children of
Israel The Ten Commandments the Bible
says here
remember the Sabbath day to keep it holy
six days shock our neighbor and do all
thy work but the seventh day is the
Sabbath of the Lord thy God in it Thou
shalt not do any work thou nor thy son
nor thy daughter thy hand thy man's
servant nor thy maid servant nor thy
cattle nor thy stranger that is within
thy gates for in six days the Lord made
Heaven and Earth the sea and all that in
them is and rest in the seventh day
wherefore the Lord bless the Sabbath day
and hallowed okay
so
God here
gives
the children of Israel
the Sabbath
after he has redeemed them
put a one in the chat if that makes
sense
he has redeemed them in other words as a
sign of their Redemption
God gives them rest
so they came unto God
and what did God give them rest
let me rephrase that
they came unto him
like if it was God speaking in the first
person he would say you all came unto me
and I gave you rest put a one in the
chat if you're all captivates
the children of Israel were given the
Sabbath again not only to remind them of
creation but also to remind them of
redemption and in fact
if we're going to Deuteronomy chapter 5
which has the the the Ten Commandments
stated again you'll notice this about
that verse of the South notice with me
Deuteronomy chapter 5 verse 12. keep the
Sabbath to sanctify it as the Lord thy
God commanded me six days saw thou labor
and do all thy work but the seventh day
is the Sabbath of the Lord thy God in it
thou shall not do any work thou Know Thy
son thy man's servant nor thy daughter
thy man servant know that made servant
watch this uh and I made so it may rest
as well as thou verse 15.
and remember
that God was a servant in the land of
Egypt and that the Lord thy God brought
the updates and through a mighty hand
and by a stretched out arm therefore the
Lord thy God commanded thee
to keep the Sabbath day
okay y'all
so now we're seeing that according to
the Old Testament
the Sabbath
is a symbol not only of the creation of
man
but also the Redemption of man
if y'all can follow me put a one in the
chat
put a one in the chat the next thing I
want you to understand about the Sabbath
is this the Sabbath
was given before the sanctuary
and he said God so what does that have
to do anything please follow along we're
simply building a foundation in the Old
Testament right now because what we
really want to find out is what does the
New Testament say about the South but in
order for us to rightly determine
rightly understand the New Testament we
need to understand the Sabbath in the
Old Testament
so watch this go with me to Exodus
chapter 16.
it's put up on the screen
Exodus chapter 16 and verse 25 the Bible
says and Moses said not please no keep
it up on the screen this is Exodus 16.
they have been delivered out of Egypt
but we have not yet gotten to Exodus 25.
something happens in Exodus 25 which I
will show you in a second but please
follow this carefully
especially those of you who may be
adversarial to the Sabbath right now I
if you're watching this because you're
trying to find holes to pop to poke
holes just I I plead with you lay that
mentality aside for a second and just
and just follow this carefully
in Exodus 16 verse 25 we have here uh
God some of the children of Israel that
he's going to Reign man about them and
they're not to gather any mana on the
seventh day he's giving them the Sabbath
in Exodus chapter 16. he gives it to
them again in Exodus chapter 20 right at
the mount at Mount Sinai now it is not
until we get to Exodus 25
that the Bible says and let them make me
a century that I may dwell among them
according to all that I show thee after
the pattern of the Tabernacle and the
pattern of all the instruments thereof
even so shall you make them okay so
let's come back
let's come back and and let's see if we
can understand it so the Sabbath
was given back in creation
as a sign of creation
it was also given
to the children of Israel
after they were redeemed from Egypt it
is a sign of redemption remember that I
delayed with you remember that I created
the world those are the two things we're
called to remember create God's creative
power and God's Redemptive power
if if anybody asked the question why
would if the devil hates the Sabbath why
would he hate it I just want you to keep
that question in the back of your mind
so far we see the Sabbath is the symbol
of God's creative power it is not the
creative power of God itself it is the
symbol of his creative power it is the
symbol of his Redemptive power now we
see that the Sabbath was given before
the children of Israel received the
sanctuary instructions in Exodus chapter
25. that's King that is crucial
let me show you something else Not only
was the Sabbath given before the
sanctuary service was introduced to the
children of Israel it was also given
outside of sacrifices and offerings
so let me break this down for you let's
go back to the screen and we're going to
go to the Book of Leviticus chapter 23.
in Leviticus chapter 23 you you have a
list of the feast days
of the children of Israel
and I want you to notice the first one
mentioned is the Sabbath six days soft
work be done but the seventh day is the
Sabbath of rest a holy convocation you
shall do no work therein it is the
Sabbath of the Lord in all your
dwellings now I want you to notice
something here
that's all it says about the Sabbath in
verse 3.
now it goes on to talk about the
Passover in verse 8.
you shall offer an offering made by fire
let me ask you a question
what is connected with the Passover
come on you guys what is connected with
the Passover
in order to keep Passover you must also
do what
you must also make and according to the
text make it a lot
okay
make an offering
there must be a sacrifice connected with
Passover are y'all with me
that's what the text says
let's keep going it talks about the
first fruits in verse 12 and you shall
offer that day when you wave the sheath
I he lamb without blemish another
offering how about the Feast of
Pentecost you shall offer with bread
seven Lambs without blemish okay what
about Trumpets the Feast of trumpets you
should do not serve all work they're in
but you shall offer an offering made by
fire unto the Lord what about atonement
you shall offer an offer by fire what
about the defeats of Tabernacles he's an
offer an offering made by fire unto the
Lord so what I want you to note here
is that with the exception of the
Sabbath
all the feast days were connected with
sacrifices and offerings are y'all with
me so far
now uh you're going to find that the
children Israel made offerings on the
Sabbath so I'm not saying that there
were no offerings that they were not
office bails out what I'm saying is that
offerings were not required in order to
keep the Sabbath however offerings were
required in order to keep Passover
unleavened bread first fruits which also
were called sabbaths by the way you'll
see that right there in Leviticus 23. so
please note the following just recapping
number one the Sabbath was given at
creation it is a sign of God's creative
power it was also given when the
children of Israel came out of Egypt it
is a sign of God's Redemptive power it
was given before the sanctuary
meaning it was not given in connection
with the sanctuary service are you
understanding what I'm saying the
century service was given in Exodus 25
the Sabbath had been given back in
Genesis 2 also in in in Exodus 16 also
in Exodus 20. it was given outside
of the sanctuary instructions the
sanctuary was not necessary in order to
keep the Sabbath are y'all with me so
far
all right
let's keep moving I want you to see
something else we're going to go to the
book of Deuteronomy chapter 12.
and here's what the Bible says in
Deuteronomy 12 verse 13 take heed to
thyself that thou offers not thy burnt
offerings in every place that thou sees
but in the place which the Lord shall
choose in one of the tribes there Thou
shalt offer thy burnt offerings and
there Thou shalt do all that I command
me so not what I want you to say by the
way let's come back for a moment
a lot of people are lazy when it comes
to understanding Bible truth
a study like this
might really I mean like you know I just
want to know and because of that I just
want to know mentality a lot of people
skip over all the principles I'm showing
you right now they skip over all these
things to to say things like the Sabbath
is not mentioned in the New Testament
therefore we don't have to keep it
that's a very lazy approach to Bible
study I'm going to show you how
erroneous that mentality is that
philosophy is in a moment but I just
want you to understand that what we're
doing right now is we're building a
solid foundation so that we can
understand things Paul says in the New
Testament that that many have taken and
misapplied and misconstrued
are y'all with me
we're gonna build this right
okay so let's keep moving so so we now
see the verse that we just read says God
is saying by the way when you give your
offerings don't give these offerings
just anywhere don't just go pick a
mountain don't just go no these
offerings are to be given in a very
specific place he says the place that I
shall put my name
all right so let's try to see what what
is he talking about here let me let's go
back to the screen I'm going to see this
again Deuteronomy 12 6 only the holy
things which I has and by vowels which
Thou shalt take go on and go on to the
place which the Lord shall choose and
thou shalt offer thy burnt offerings the
Flesh and Blood upon the altar of the
Lord by God and the blood of thy
sacrifice shall be poured out upon the
altar of the Lord thy God and thou shalt
eat the flesh so again
goddess is clearly saying here that the
offerings
and these
things connected with these offerings
must be kept in a very specific place
the place which the Lord shall choose
and what is the place that the Lord
chose let's go back to the screen and we
will see in First Kings
First Kings in fact let me finish
reading I didn't finish reading verse
verse 2. that's all thou so therefore
sacrifice the Passover unto the Lord thy
God of the flock and the herd in the
place which the Lord shall choose to
place his name there what was that place
First Kings 11 36 and unto his son will
I give one try that David my servant may
have a light always before me in
Jerusalem the city where I have chosen
to put my name there all right y'all so
come back let's come back come back to
the screen where is the place that God
says sacrifices and offerings must take
place
where is that place
that place is Jerusalem
listen carefully
once God established Jerusalem Passover
unleavened bread panic all these feasts
were to be kept there the sacrifices
were to be were to be done there not any
place we chose that in fact if you did
orphans and sacrifices in any place
other than that you were breaking the
Commandment of God
let's go back to the screen and I want
you to notice again First Chronicles
chapter 22 verse 19 Now set your heart
and your soul to seek the Lord your God
Arise therefore and they'll be the
sanctuary of the Lord God to bring the
Ark of the Covenant of the Lord and the
holy justice of God into the house that
is to be built to the name of the Lord
come back with me
so what we've just learned is that the
place where the Lord was going to put
his name was number one Jerusalem number
two the sanctuary listen carefully to me
Passover unleavened bread first fruits
uh Pentecost uh
trumpets Tabernacles daily atonement
were all to be kept with sacrifices and
those sacrifices could only be done in
the temple and the temple was to be
found in Jerusalem both of which have
the name of God put there
are y'all with me please keep this in
mind
that these feasts were therefore local
feasts they could not be kept anywhere
in the world
or you were breaking the Commandment of
God
the Sabbath however was a global
phenomenon are y'all with me
come on y'all put that one in the chat
put that one inside for those of you who
are anti-sabbath right now put that one
in the chat I'm just showing you what's
an Old Testament you can agree with that
it's all right it's okay
so so son follow this now but Sabbath
was Universal
it was a sign of God's creation a sign
of God's Redemptive power and it was
given outside of the sanctuary outside
of Jerusalem meaning it was Global in
scope and there were no sacrifices or
offerings necessary to keep the Sabbath
all right I got one more point to show
you then we're going into the New
Testament let's go back to the Book of
Exodus chapter 12. and exodus 12 48 When
a Stranger self sojourned with thee and
will keep the Passover to the Lord let
all his males be circumcised and let and
then let them come near and keep it me
somebody is one that is born in the land
for no uncircumcised person shall eat
their own so the last thing I want you
to note as far as the Old Testament goes
is this
if anyone wanted to keep the Passover
unleavened bread first fruits or any
other of those feasts that were to be
kept in Jerusalem that you have to be
involved in that you have to go to the
sanctuary they had to be circumcised
circumcision was the was the was the
doorway into keeping these feasts and
Tabernacle of these feasts and
sacrifices Etc however
the Sabbath required no circumcision you
don't you didn't have to be circumcised
in order to keep the Sabbath Adam and
Eve
yeah
the children of Israel uh uh back there
in in in Exodus chapter 16 and we know
that circumstances have been given to
Abraham but after the children of Israel
come out of Egypt God says for the
stranger listen carefully the stranger
that wants to keep the Passover he must
be circumcised
now how do we know that circumcision was
not necessary to keep the South well
let's just go to one more verse in the
Old Testament Isaiah chapter 56. Isaiah
56 and I want you to note what verse 2
says put it up on the screen
Isaiah 56
verse 2. the Bible says blessed is a man
that doeth this the son of man that laid
hold on it that keepeth the Sabbath from
polluting it and keeping his hand from
doing an evil neither let the son of a
stranger that has joined himself for the
Lord speaks saying the Lord has utterly
separated me from his people neither let
the eunuch
neither let the eunuch say behold I am a
dry tree for thus say the Lord unto the
eunuchs that keep my sabbaths and choose
the things that please me and take hold
of my Covenant so what we clearly see
here is that a unit who could not have
been circumcised God said you can keep
this out
and if you keep the Sabbath I'm going to
do something special for you
all right
we just finished our study of the Old
Testament how y'all doing
put a seven in the chat if y'all did
okay with this put a seven in the chat I
got it that's pretty clear and simple
um straightforward I just laid out right
the whole Old Testament the sound from
beginning all the way down to the the
final the the whole Old Testament the
final book of the Old Testament
no one debates that the Sabbath was kept
in Jerusalem that the Sabbath was kept
by the Jews and it was the seventh day
The Seventh-Day Friday Sunday that's not
a debate here no one goes to the Old
Testament to try to prove that Sabbath
is no longer needed to be kept because
it was kept in this in the Old Testament
without question
so now let's go to the New Testament but
we're going to focus just on the gospels
and and so far we have no evidence that
God disdained the Sabbath in the Old
Testament so now if he does if God
descends if God does not want us to keep
the Sabbath we're going to have to find
the evidence either in Matthew Mark Luke
and John and if it's not there in the
gospels then all we have left is the
book of Acts to the book of to the Book
of Revelation so we're going to spend
just a little time on the gospels are
y'all ready
we know that Jesus kept the Sabbath
um in the gospels that's not a question
but but some people like to say that
actually Jesus broke the Sabbath in the
new in in the gospels and I just want to
go to that very quickly let's because
that's all we're going to touch on in
the gospel we want to get to the book of
Acts
so let's go ahead and we're going to
look at
um look at the next slide uh let's go
we're looking at the gospels and by the
way Jesus said in John 15 10 if you keep
my Commandments you shall abide in my
love even as I have kept my father
through Commandments under by me his
love so we know that Jesus kept his
father's Commandments right no question
about that John 14 15 if you love me
keep my Commandments
that's not a question Jesus kept his
father's commandments so my other
question is what about the Sabbath and
and here's a very here's a favorite text
of people who like to say that the
Sabbath began to be weakened in the New
Testament so let's look at Isaiah John
chapter 5 verse 18. therefore the Jews
sought the more to kill him because he
not only had broken the Sabbath but said
also that God was his father making
himself equal with God so here pastor it
clearly says that Jesus broke the
Sabbath
what more do you need Pastor and this
just refuted your whole study I want you
to fight let's ask the question
how are they accusing Jesus of breaking
the Sabbath
so let's just go back to what Jesus
actually did let's go back we're going
to go back John 5 we're still there in
John 5 and notice verse 5. and a certain
man was there which had an infirmity 38
years when Jesus saw him lie and knew
that he had been now a long time in that
case he said about to him will that be
made whole the impotent man answered sir
I have no man when the waters Waters
trouble to put me in the pool
but while I'm coming another steps down
before me
Jesus said unto him rise take up your
bed and walk
and immediately the man was made whole
and took of his bed and walked and on
the same day was the Sabbath
the Jews therefore said unto him that
was cured
it is the Sabbath day it is not lawful
for thee to carry thy bit okay
let me ask you a question real quick
um human ss20 where it talks about
um you know Donaldson not carry that
dead
after being healed remember that verse
y'all don't remember the verse
all right well do you remember the verse
where it says you're not allowed to
carry your bed on the Sabbath you
remember that verse
you don't run that verse either
maybe you don't remember that verse
because it's not in the Bible
because that's not a rule of God
maybe you don't remember that verse
because God never laid that out
in fact we're told that they claim that
Jesus has broken the Sabbath because he
cures a man and tells a man to get up
and go home take it take your bed and go
home what does it have to do stay there
until the seven hours were over and then
walk home with his bed
come on
and they're so blinded by hate toward
Jesus that they're like he broke this
out now we can either take their word
for it and say yes Jesus did bring the
Sabbath or we can take Jesus own words
let's go back to the screen
let's go back to the screen and um John
5 11. she's answered them he then oh I'm
sorry they asked the man who Who Made
Who told him to take us better walk he
answered them he that made me whole the
same Salat
then they asked him what man is it that
sit on to be take up at bed and walk
he uh and therefore did the Jews
persecute Jesus and sought to slay him
because he had done these things on the
south he healed on the south he told the
man to walk he did something good on the
Sabbath that's why they just wanted to
kill him that's why they said he was
breaking the Sabbath but according to
Jesus's own words in another account
Matthew 12 11 he said unto them what man
shall there be among you that shall have
one sheep and if it fall into a pit on
the south day will he not lay hold on it
and lift it out how much then is a man
better than a sheep wherefore it is
lawful to do well on the Sabbath days
not pause keep that up on the screen
Jesus says it is lawful to do well in
the Sabbath days
the Pharisees said it is not lawful for
you to carry and I bet on the Sabbath
day
Jesus said
it is lawful to do well on the Sabbath
days
the Pharisees said you are breaking the
Sabbath because it is not lawful for you
to carry your bed after being cured on
the Sabbath now I'm going to ask you a
question
who would you rather believe this we can
take social screen who are you going to
believe are you going to leave the
pharaoh
Jesus broke the Sabbath
or are you going to believe Jesus that
it is lawful to heal that is lawful to
do well that it is lawful to save life
on the Sabbath
okay
beyond that incident we have no other
reference
to challenge that the Sabbath was kept
by Jesus by his disciples and by
everybody else in Israel so if we're
going to find a reason to not keep the
Sabbath it is not in the Old Testament
it is not in Matthew Mark Luke and John
because they are all kept the Sabbath
and taught nothing different
now we are left
with the book of Acts to the book of to
the Book of Revelation are y'all with me
so far
we're just doing this methodical we're
we're going through the Bible
methodically we're trying to see is
there a reason to say that God has
cursed the Sabbath now before we move
into the New Testament
proper I just need to to
to show this very quickly if I can let's
go back to the screen
um did Jesus
change the Sabbath from the first day of
the week from the seventh day that we
took the first day of the week
it's very simply put there are eight
verses in the whole new testament
relating to the first day of the week
eight verses in the whole new testament
all together only eight if we're gonna
find that God chains us out from the
seventh day of the week to the first day
of the week the cause of the
resurrection of Jesus which it should
State we need to find it in one of these
eight Texas tests Texas
all right so let's go here are the first
five
here are the first five
and these first five all they do is make
a reference to the fact that it was the
first day of the week when Mary
Magdalene went to the tomb that's all it
says doesn't say anything about the
Sabbath doesn't say anything about God
changed the day from from Saturday to
Sunday nothing of the sort in the end of
the Sabbath as it began to go on toward
the first day of the week so the first
day of the week of Sunday Came Mary
Magdalene near the Mary to see to see
the supper
that's Matthew 28 1. Mark 16 2. says the
same thing Mark 69 now when Jesus was
raised in the first day of the week
Matthew 24 1. now it was from the first
day of the week when it was very early
in the morning Matthew 20 verse 1 the
first day of the week Comes Mary
Magdalene early when it was yet dark
until Saturday none of these verses say
that Sunday is the new Sabbath because
Jesus rose from the grave
are y'all with me
okay
what about John 2019
there's the next one number six
then the same day at evening being the
first day of the week when the doors
were shut where the disciples were
assembled worshiping in Joy Keeping the
new South
no the disciples were assembled for what
fear of the Jews
this is not a worship service
they are gathered out of fear and it
happens to be on the first day of the
week being gathered out of fear on the
first day of the week does not make the
first day of the week holy
are y'all with me so far
by the way only God can make something
holy and when God makes something holy
he clearly declares it
I don't have any power to sanctify
Tuesday or to sanctify a day of the week
the Sabbath is not myself I the Sabbath
is the Sabbath of the Lord he is the one
that's Sanctified it and declared and
holy now if God declares something holy
and I go back and try to unbless what
God blessed God y'all remember
um that false prophet
back there with the children of Israel
and a donkey
remember how he tried to curse what God
had blessed that's a dangerous thing
y'all I'm just saying
so God blesses something
the only one that can unblessed is God
himself
and if God is going to bless something
the only one that can bless that thing
is God himself so if Sunday is the new
blessed day we better find a verse
clearly stating that God blessed it and
Sanctified it and hallowed it but so far
out of the eight verses we just looked
at six and none of them say anything of
the Soul what about the last two
let's go to first to the book of Acts
chapter 20 verse 7. and upon the first
day of the week this is the book of Acts
now upon the first day of the week when
the disciples came together to break
bread Paul preached unto them ready to
depart on the moral and continue the
speech until midnight okay
so my question is does breaking bread on
a particular day of the week make that
day holy now remember we just said only
God can make something holy and in order
for him to make something holy he
declares it holy go just read the Old
Testament anything that was holy God
spank it and said the priests they are
holding on to me this it is holding on
to me the sanctuary it is only this is
Holiness he declared the things holy
that he wanted only
does breaking bread on a certain day of
the week make that day holy
nowhere in the Bible do I find that
principle do I find that I don't find
that at all
not only is that the case but I want you
to know that the disciples did not just
break bread on the first day of the week
because according to the book of Acts
Same Book of Acts chapter 2 verse 46 and
they continuing daily with one according
to the temple and breaking bread from
house to house did eat their meat with
gladness and singleness apart okay so
what do we see here the early church met
every day of the week they met
daily this does not sanctify every day
of the week having a church meeting does
not make the day holy that's not what we
read in the Commandment is it on the
seventh day you shall go to church and
make that day Holy by going to church
so I believe we ought to be in church
and not forsake the fellowship of the of
the assembling of the Brethren together
the Sabbath commandment is Holy with or
without church service
it is not being in church on a certain
day that makes a day holy it is the fact
that God rested on that day that God
himself declared that day holy
that's what makes the day holy so the
disciples breaking bread on Sunday on
Saturday then breaking bread on Saturday
doesn't make Saturday holy it was God
resting on Saturday that made Saturday
holy so they could be they could be
breaking bread every day of the week
Monday is not holy Tuesday about holy
way those are work days Days in which
you can do your own thing days in which
you have to live and when I say you're
all be near yourself I mean days in
which you're not required to keep it
holy by not working by refraining from
all secular activity
secular activity is not evil in and of
itself
but to keep the Sabbath holy requires
you to refrain
from everything secular
all right so now we see that the
disciples breaking bread on a day does
not make that day holy nor the fact that
they broke dread every day makes every
day holy beloved meet every day of the
week that's not what the Commandment is
saying
so you can meet hey I worship God every
day of the week you're supposed to
worship God every day of the week but
the Sabbath has been set aside as a
memorial of his creative power and his
Redemptive power and he says I want you
to remember that
keep it holy
okay what about the last one last one
and then we're getting into the New
Testament First Corinthians chapter 6
and verse two upon the first day of the
week then every one of you lay by him in
store as God has prospered him that
there be no Gatherings when I come
so again you all catch the point right
making a collection or or sending money
aside on the first day of the week does
not I don't read anywhere in the Bible
where if I if I decide that on Monday
I'm gonna set some money aside that that
makes Monday holy
the text is not here speaking of a new
sound
or someone that the church the early
church met particularly on the first day
of the week because as we've just seen
the early church met every day of the
week
you can meet every day of the week this
no one's saying don't meet on it on any
other day of the week but Sabbath no the
early church meant every day of the week
but they still kept the Sabbath
all right just let me show you something
and then we're gonna move on back up on
the Stream these are the different
translations of that same verse just so
you could see that this was not a church
gathering on the first day of the week
watch this every first day of the week
each one of each one is to put aside
food at home
storing up whatever he made whatever he
may be prospered in so that there need
not be any collections when I come
here's another one on the first of the
week let each of you put by at home
and that's what in the King James when
it says lay by him in store it means to
put up in your own place that's why it's
you see it translated lay by him at home
The Good News Bible every Sunday each of
you must put aside some money in
proportion to what you have earned you
are the Erb version on the first day of
the week each of you should take some of
your money and put it in a special place
what the what the text is actually
saying here is that the people were
after the sample was over and now it's
time to get back to your work week make
sure you lay aside some money your
earnings from the week before so that
when I come and I make up and I and I
collect this offering everything's
already in place this had nothing to do
with a Sunday worship service last one
last one is found in Revelation chapter
one verse 10. I was in the spirit on the
Lord's day and heard behind me a great
voice as of the trumpet and people say
see Pastor this is the Lord's day this
is the first day of the week the problem
with that is that you cannot go line up
online precept upon precept and prove
that the Lord's day is the first day of
the week because nowhere in the Bible
does it ever call the first day of the
week the Lord's Day in fact if you go to
Isaiah 58 you will see him calling the
Sabbath his holy day here it is on the
screen Isaiah 15 verse 13 if God turn
away thy foot from the south and from
doing thy pleasure on my holy day so God
clearly calls the Sabbath his day the
day of the Lord all right
we're going to pause for a second
let's come back to the screen how are
y'all doing so far
how y'all doing so far I I just we're
just walking through we're just walking
through it but I'm trying to lay a
foundation so we've now seen it in the
Old Testament we have no reason to
believe that God despise the Sabbath in
the books of Matthew Mark Luke and John
we have no reason to believe that
somehow Jesus did not keep the Sabbath
the disciples somehow did not keep the
Sabbath so now now what we have now what
we have left by the way we find no
evidence that that Jesus or the
disciples changed the the day from
Sabbath to the first day of the week and
so with that on the side now we've just
got now we just have a few things left
we just got the New Testament we just
got the book of Acts to the Book of
Revelation and and what I want you to
understand here is really reason this is
like the meat of the message every
everything I shared before is like you
know
this is the meat
we're going to culminate with the book
of Hebrews and you're going to see
something mind-blowing you're going to
wonder why was Pastor telling us all
this stuff in the beginning about you
know when the soccer was given and white
was giving the fourth this this and this
because I'm setting a foundation for you
to see the clear beauty of Truth Listen
to me y'all truth is beautiful
error is always going to leave you with
more questions than you have answers
because error doesn't make sense it
might look like it made sense for us oh
man this is true but when you really
start to break it down oh wait a minute
huh
so watch this
uh the argument is is given
that the Sabbath has not been restated
in the New Testament right the book of
Acts onward that it's you know all the
other Commandments are restated but the
Sabbath is not restated therefore we no
longer need to keep it
now I don't know where that principle
came from
I have no idea who made it up but a lot
of people seem to buy into that as if it
is a Biblical principle here's the
problem with that
let's just take for a moment the idea
that the Sabbath is not restated in the
new let's just say that that's the case
I'm going to ask you a question let's
let's go to the screen and uh I want you
to check this out okay
Leviticus 18 6 none of you shall
approach to any that is near of kin to
him
to uncover their nakedness I am the Lord
thank you
verse 23. neither shall not lied with
any beats to defile thyself with neither
saw any woman stand for Beast to lie
down there until it is confusion now
here's my question you guys okay
um
bestiality is not repeated in the New
Testament
the command not to sleep with animals
not to have sex with animals is not
explicitly repeated in the New Testament
the Commandment to not lie with your
nearest of kin is not repeated in the
New Testament there's one incident of a
man being rebuked for for marrying his
mother-in-law but as far as your blood
you know Sister Uncle your your family
your nearest Akin there's no commandment
in the New Testament addressing this
it's not restated
so what are we going to do with that yo
how are we gonna are we going to say
that it is now okay to have sex with
animals because it is not explicitly
restating in the New Testament
is that what we're gonna say because if
we're going to say that
it's it's
open season for Christians there's a lot
of stuff we can do now
that weren't that are not explicitly
restated in the New Testament do y'all
see the problem with that
arson look at this
um
Exodus 22 verse 6 if fire break out and
catch and Thorns so that the sacks of
corn or standing corn or the field be
consumed there with he that came with
the fire must shortening restitution
that's just arson arson's not repeated
in the New Testament is it all right for
us to go set fire to stuff
the idea that if it's not mentioned in
the New Testament then we don't have to
keep it is is fallacious it's fallacy
it's it's it's it's it's it's a poor
principle
by which to determine what is truth and
what is error
so with that said let's go ahead and now
begin to break down the New Testament
teaching oh man this is this is the meat
y'all this is the means
um so here's what we want to do
we need to put flesh and blood into this
all right by the way how y'all doing so
far are we good
I know at the beginning we were having
like a bunch of technical difficulties
and I hope by my sound is good because
ah I would hate it if the sound is
hollow but don't tell me I don't even
want to know I'm flowing so just don't
tell me
I just pray that everything is going
good all right
all right listen
um
there's as we look at the New Testament
Church the early church we need to
understand that when Jesus died was
buried and then resurrected and ascended
listen to me y'all when he ascended to
heaven
it was not like all of a sudden the
early church now had the whole truth
like now they understood everything oh
okay
um we don't need to do this anymore
circumstances is no longer necessary
that's not how it unfolded
first of all Jesus spent 40 days with
them going back over the scriptures
that's number one number two you're
going to see
that the church was learning in
progression can y'all say that with me
just put in the chat progression
they were understanding in progression
and by the way
you need to understand that they didn't
have TVs in those days
they didn't have cell phones they didn't
have social media right today in social
media something happens and it goes on
social media and the whole world knows
about it in an instant it wasn't like
that back in those days so when a when a
new understanding came to the church it
wasn't like everybody now has that
understanding letters have to take time
to travel to churches and and and and
and people have to take time to like
okay well what was Paul saying over
there in in this place and so they were
learning in progression
so so for example
we know that in Acts 2 the spirit is
poured out and and Peter preaches his
first sermon
but it's not until Acts chapter 10 that
that Peter has given the understanding
that the gospel is supposed to go to the
Gentiles
are y'all with me
in Acts 10 he's like oh he's got a
vision that all right so the gospel is
not just supposed to go to to us as as
Jews but it's all supposed supposed to
go to the Gentiles whoever those
Gentiles may be all right uh that's a
whole other subject we're going to deal
with another time not relevant to this
study right now
but and acts 10 there's that Revelation
ah now he's got to go explain to the
church hey God gave me a vision in this
Vision I saw all kinds of unclean
animals and then I was like the normal
side rise can't eat I'm like I've never
eaten anything on clean and God says
what I've cleansed do not call that
common and then he says God show me I
shall not call any man Gentile common or
unclean so this is the church growing
and understanding oh okay we we can
spread the gospel the Gentiles okay so
now they start spreading the gospel the
Gentiles and what's happening is as a
Gentiles are coming in they're like okay
you got to be circumcised you need to
keep the law of Moses
Passover I'll never read first thoughts
right
all these festivals are peace
so it's not until Acts chapter 15 at the
Jerusalem Council where watch this let's
go back to the stream I'm building
something here I want you to see let's
go back to the screen
and in Acts 15 it says but there rose up
certain of the sect of the Pharisees
which believe so these are believed in
Jews believe in Pharisees saying that it
is needful to circumcise them and to
command them to keep the law of Moses
verse 6 and the apostles and the elders
came together for to consider the matter
now pause for a second here pause for a
second
they're coming together to consider the
matter I need you to understand
something in our day as someone came to
me and said hey people are being told
that they need to be circumcised would
we be considering that
it would be like no of course the Bible
says and we be very clear on it but in
that time they're actually coming
together to be like um
what do we do with this
Howie so they're considering it and and
let's go back to the screen notice this
and when there have been much disputing
Peter rolls up much distance much
disputing much back and forth Peter rose
up and said unto them men and Berlin you
know that a good while ago God made
Choice Among Us that Gentiles by my
mouth should hear the word of the gospel
and believe
and after his his speech here's what it
says wherefore my sentences that we
trouble not them which from among the
Gentiles are turned to God but that we
write unto them that they abstained from
pollutions of idols and from fornication
and from being strangled and from blood
so now you see the church growing in
their understanding okay the Gentiles
that we've been started baptizing since
acts 10 we don't need to tell them we
don't need to to command them to keep
the law of Moses we don't need to tell
them to be circumcised uh here's what
they need to know
so you see progression here by the way
some have said see the Sabbath isn't on
this list
which you know I gotta tell you is like
I don't know it's it's
sleeping with animals is not on that
list
stealing is not on that list
just go down the list of and think how
many things are not on the list they
mentioned Idols fornication pollution uh
uh uh strangled uh animal strangled and
blood
think about how many things are not
mentioned on that list for us to be like
well the Sabbath wasn't required me for
them because it wasn't meant to the next
15 is again it's
that it's it's open season for what
Gentiles can do then
all right so let's keep moving we're
almost there guys we're we are almost
there
um
let's go to acts 21 back button screen
that's 21 that's 21 I want you to notice
this
so this is talking about Paul then take
and purify that purify with them and be
in charge with them that they may shave
their heads and all may know those
things whereof they were informed
concerning me talking about Paul they're
telling Paul Paul you need to go do
these things because the Jews think
you're not keeping the law
so it says wherefore their informed
concerning me are nothing but that thou
also thyself walk is quarterly and Keep
Us Alive that's something that's
touching the Gentiles which believe we
have written and concluded that they
observe no such things save only that
they keep themselves from things from
things off to idols and from blood and
from strangled and from fornication then
Paul took them in the next day purifying
him himself with them entered into the
temple to signify the accomplishment of
the days of purification until that an
offering should be offered for every one
of them not pause for a second pause for
a second huh
an offering
what
an offering now some people have been
like well Paul was just doing this to X
Y and Z to show that you know he wasn't
off the wall or one of the reasons I
just want you to know I want you to
understand
that it wasn't
day before Christ's death the church
thinks this day after Christ's death the
church now has all the light and now
they understand everything they were
growing in progression are y'all with me
do you understand what I'm saying
foreign
there is silence in the New Testament
the Sabbath is a pretty big issue for
the Jews
there is silence in the New Testament
regarding any attempted change by Paul
or the disciples or Jesus himself if
they were going to try to change the
Sabbath it would have been Warfare you
would have heard about it in the book of
Acts
we find no such argument
all right
it is not until we get to the Book of
Romans that you you begin to see
writings about the difference between
Jews and Gentiles is non-existent they
are growing in that we get to the book
of Galatians and Ephesians and
Colossians and now they're they're
working out this thing called Faith
versus works right the righteousness of
the law versus faith in Christ these
books are chronicling as it were their
progression and their understanding of
the Gospel as it's unfolding to them are
y'all with me
now the reason why I'm sending you up
here is because I want you to see
something I want you to understand
something very clearly
in Colossians chapter two let's go to
the screen Colossians chapter 2 and we
are almost there guys the the bombshell
is being saved for last okay
so just follow me
just follow me
Colossians 2
13. and you being dead in your sins and
uncertain and the and the other services
on the flesh as he quickened together
with him haven't forgiven you all your
trespasses blotting up a handwriting
ordinances that was against us so now we
see that Paul is writing here that
something's been plotted out which was
contrary to us and took it out of the
way man and it's across and having small
principalities and Powers he made a show
of them openly triumphed him over the
minute let no man therefore judge you in
meat or in drink or in respect of a holy
day or of the new moon or of the Sabbath
days which are a shadow of things to
come but the body is of Christ and
beloved here is where people absolutely
lose their life yes
there is the verse it clearly says that
we no longer need to worry about the
Sabbath
but the only way you could come to a
conclusion like that is to be totally
ignorant of everything that we just
talked about before
because what we're going to see is that
Paul is going to clarify this in the
book of Hebrews
and this is my loyal are you ready for
this
okay Barrel I beat you to it I beat you
to it uh Colossians 2 16. right
let no man judge you in needs drinks
holy days new moons and the sabbaths the
Sabbath days which were a shadow of
things to come
we know that it knows we just mentioned
in the Old Testament earlier in the Old
Testament that all these other festivals
pass over on government first fruits
were all known as salads you can find
that in Leviticus track 23 is Paul
talking here that all the holy days are
gone or done away with or is he making a
distinction of something that was a
shadow of things to come well
let's find out let's find out and to
find out we're going to close our study
in the book of Hebrews let's go to the
screen this is where we're closing it
off y'all
we're in the book of Hebrews and here's
what I want you to understand this is
crucial to understand the book of
Hebrews is written
most Scholars agree the book of Hebrews
was written somewhere between 65 and 69
A.D
all right why is that significant
in Hebrews 5 verse 1
the Bible says for every priest every
high priest taken from among men is
ordained for men in things pertaining to
God that he may offer both gifts and
sacrifices for sins I'm just going to
stop right there
Hebrews 5 1 is written in the present
tense
let me say that again I want you to come
back come back to the screen Hebrews 5 1
is written in present tense what does
that mean
foreign 65 whenever this book was
written somewhere between 65 and 69 A.D
Paul is speaking presently the sanctuary
is still standing
Twitter one in the chat if you
understand that this is this is crucial
y'all the sanctuary is still standing
all right let's go back to the screen
he's writing in present tense
in Hebrews 8 he begins to talk about the
Covenant and he says for if the first
Covenant had been faultless then should
no place have been solved for the second
for finding fault with them he said
behold
the days come save the Lord when I will
make a New Covenant with the house of
Israel and with the house of Judah not
according to the Covenant that I made
with their fathers in the day when I
took them by the hand to lead them out
of the land of Egypt because they
continued not in my Covenant and I
regarded them not saved the Lord
for this is the color that I will make
with the house of Israel after those
days say the Lord I will put my laws
into their minds and write them in their
hearts and I will be the name of God and
they shall be to your people in that he
said verse 13 in that he said a New
Covenant he has made the first o now
that which the cave and waxing old is
ready to vanish away
pause for a second y'all
is ready to vanish away wait a minute
hold on Paul
ready to vanish away you mean it hasn't
vanished
bro how can you say that it is 65 to 69
A.D how can you be writing in 65 to 69
A.D that the old Covenant is getting
ready
so that is the way
Paul are you mistaken
wait a minute that was vanished at the
cross Paul
that was vanished you know on the day of
Pentecost when everybody understood oh
yeah these are the things we need to do
now and these things are all done away
we're good to go Paul in 65 somewhere
between 65 to 698 is saying the old
Covenant is getting ready to disappear
but what I need you to understand that
all we need to do now is to look for
what disappeared shortly after that to
let us know oh these are the things that
we no longer need to keep
are y'all following me I know it was a
long bit billable but not to listen to
me sometimes truth requires deep study
sometimes truth requires deep Long stay
and I hope I hope you're excited right
now
because it's as if God himself is going
to tell us listen and for the church
y'all see you know if there's some
confusion about what should still be
observed and what is about I myself
I'm going to take away the old couple
and Paul in 65 to 69 A.D writes the old
Covenant is about to vanish now come on
I need you to see this let's go back to
the screen we're just going to look at
some different translations the AFV and
speaking of a New Covenant he has made
the first Covenant obsolete now that
which has become old and is obviously is
about to disappear
will soon disappear
is ready to vanish away
will soon disappear hmm
what is about to disappear Paul pray
tell us
let's go to Hebrews 9. Hebrews 9.
then verily the first Covenant now watch
this yeah
the first Covenant had also ordinances
of divine service and a worldly
Sanctuary okay so there's a sanctuary
connected with the first Covenant before
there was a tabernacle made the first
ring was a Candlestick at the table and
the shoe grid which is called the
sanctuary and after the second video The
Tabernacle was called the holiest of all
number six now watch this up now when
these things were thus ordained back
there in Exodus Exodus 25. the priest
went always into the first Tabernacle
accomplishing the service of God the one
that's still standing right now yo
as part is Right 65 to 60 90. but into
the second when the high priest alone
once every year not without blood which
he offered for himself for The Heirs of
the people now watch this what Heavenly
Father please Lord
give this Christmas gift to people who
are seeking for truth who are watching
right now pleading for a greater
understanding give them
with truth
in Jesus name I pray amen
first Samuel
the Holy Ghost this signify
that the way into the holiest was not
was of all was not yet made manifest
while as the first Tabernacle was
standing now watch this
which was a figure for the time present
in which were offered both gifts
and sacrifices that could not make him
that did the service perfect as
pertaining to the conscience which stood
also in needs
and drinks and diverse Washings and
Cardinal ordinances
imposed on them until the time of
reformation
uh
so so come back with me y'all come back
with me come back with me so what Paul
is saying here
is that the first Covenant
which contained The Sanctuary
had connected with that Sanctuary
ordinances and services things that all
were were connected with the sanctuary
that did not make the cover there to the
those coming onto the oh and doing the
service perfect it could
so it now becomes obvious
that is that
thing that was connected with the old
Covenant Jerusalem these feasts must be
kept in Jerusalem the sacrifices must be
done in connection with the temple it
now becomes clear that if the temple is
done away with
then also all the things connected with
the temple that were part of the temple
service that were dependent upon Temple
service would also be done away with
oh man doesn't that simplify things
so watch this y'all
we know
that something happened
in 70 A.D we know that right y'all know
something happened in 70 80.
just a few years after Paul is writing
the old Covenant is about to banish away
meaning that all Sanctuary is about to
vanish away meaning the thing connected
with the sanctuary of Jerusalem is about
to be
um hold on
I said in Matthew 24
that not one stone would be left upon
another in Jerusalem or in the temple we
know that in 70 A.D the temple was
destroyed as well as Jerusalem so guess
what y'all if there is no Jerusalem and
if there is no Temple can the Passover
be kept yes or no
any confusion in the church hey we
should still be keeping Passover uh no
we didn't any confusion was settled when
Jerusalem was destroyed because when
Jerusalem was destroyed and the temple
was destroyed you can no longer keep the
Passover why because God said you can't
keep the Passover wherever you want to
you have to keep it where I put my name
otherwise you're doing just like they
even did before you
so watch this Passover
Century wasn't necessary to keep that
Feast of unleavened bread Center wasn't
necessary to keep that first Fruits
Center was necessary
Pentacles
Dave atonement
Feast of Tabernacles sacrifices
offerings all you could do none of that
without the sanctuary and without
Jerusalem both are destroyed meaning
along with Jerusalem being destroyed at
the sanctuary being destroyed God
himself tells us
this is what is no longer needed
let me ask you a question
can one keep the Sabbath outside of
Jerusalem yes or no
yes or no
can one keep the Sabbath in Mexico
can one keep the Sabbath
in Jamaica
can one keep the Sabbath in Russia
can one keep it is there any
requirements that you have to be in a
certain place namely Jerusalem to keep
this out
no requirement
does one need to be circumcised
in order to keep the South
no such requirement
does one need the sanctuary
in order to keep the South
no
why because there are no sacrifices or
offerings connected with the Sabbath you
don't have to sacrifice in order to keep
the Sabbath you have to sacrifice in
order to keep the Passover first fruits
Undead which are all settless which now
helps us to understand that when Paul is
writing it in Colossians 2 let no man
judge you by these things which are a
shadow of things to come ah he's not
talking about The Seventh-Day Sabbath
which is a sign of God's creative power
and his Redemptive power he's talking
about everything connected with the old
Covenants
now that we have that out the way
let's talk about why and just please
just give me a few more moments okay
let's just talk about why then should we
as Christians still keep the Sabbath one
of the Ten Commandments it is a part of
the New Covenant y'all why should by the
way by the way I forgot to mention while
Paul says that something was to vanish
away he also said that something was
going to remain you want to know what
that thing was that he said was going to
remain come to the screen with me and
please notice this in the same book
Hebrews chapter 4
their remaineth therefore and rest to
the people of god wow so hold on the
sanctuary the Covenant was going to
decay
but there remains a risk to the people
of God
for he that entered into his rest has
also ceased from his own works as God
did for his pointing back to the Sabbath
let us labor therefore to enter into
that Restless amen father the same
example of unbelief wow come on come on
SO Paul says by the way just in case you
think that there's no longer a salad for
the people of God no no no no that
remains
that remains now some people say wait a
minute Pastor that Sabbath is a sign of
the ultimate Sabbath that's going to be
in the future I get that too yes he's
talking about that as well but what I
need you to understand is that that
being the case this is
in the Old Testament the Sabbath pointed
backward to Creation
in the New Testament through the death
of Christ the Sabbath right now points
forward to the Heavenly Promised Land
that means we are supposed to be keeping
it
we are supposed to be keeping it not
only as a as a memorial for what God did
a creation
but also as a reminder of what heaven is
going to be like
come back to the spirit I need you to
see this go back to the screen
there remains therefore a day of rest
for the people of God there remains a
Sabbath rest for the people of God so
then there remains a cell of the rest
for the people of God so then there
remains a Sabbath rest for the people of
God of God there remains therefore
inside of the rest of the people of God
they sold that there is still a Sabbath
keeping for the people of God there
remains then a solid rest for the people
of God there remains then a Sabbath for
the people of Elohim Beloved the Sabbath
remains while the old Covenant was done
away
we cannot get any clearer than this
all right
why should we keep this out
why should we keep the Sabbath come on
y'all
follow me follow John 14.
John 14 verse 2 in My Father's House of
many mansions if it were not so I would
have told you I go to prepare a place
for you and if I go under prayer please
for you I will come again and receive
you unto myself that where I am there
you may be awesome so God has gone to
prepare a place for us and he's going to
receive us unto himself you remember
what it said back in the Old Testament
how God brought the children of Israel
out of bondage unto himself
how Jesus said in the New Testament come
unto me all ye that neighbor and are
heavy dating and I will give you just as
he gave him rest in the Old Testament he
seeks with the same individual now
follow him follow
in Colossians it says this lie not one
to another seeing that you have put off
the old man with his deeds and put on
the new man which is renewed in the
knowledge after the image of him that
created him so let me ask you a question
when you when you come to Christ does he
recreate you
does God recreate you does Christ
yes
let me ask you a question what is the
symbol of God's creative power
it's the South
beloved when you have been recreated in
the image of God the Sabbath is the
celebration of your Recreation
so often we think of the Sabbath as a
bunch of don'ts you can't do this and
you can't do that but look at the
Sabbath is the sign the reminder that
God has made you a new creation and you
and God says I want you to celebrate
that every seven days every time you
think of the Sabbath every time you keep
the Sabbath holy you are acknowledging
that I am the Lord that recreated you
that Sanctified you
it doesn't stop there come back with me
I'm just gonna Ephesians says the same
thing and where his workmanship but now
I want to go to Matthew 121. he shall
bring from the son and I shall call his
name Jesus for he shall save his people
from their sins I need you to understand
this that when you are being saved from
your sins that is God redeeming you that
is redemption happening and beloved
listen just as God led the children of
Israel out of Egyptian captivity and
gave them the Sabbath as a sign that
they were delivered so he leads us out
of the Captivity of our sins and gives
us the Sabbath as a reminder of our
Redemption thus the Sabbath is to remind
me not only that God has recreated me
but that he has redeemed me
every seventh day is a celebration an
official celebration of what Christ has
done in my life no beloved this is not
legalism
this is the demonstration of the power
of God in one's life
all right
let me just do this let me just do this
please I promise you promise you let's
go back to the screen we're just going
to stand on the screen okay I'm gonna
try to run through the rest of these
slides just follow me Jeremiah 6 16 just
say the Lord stand thee in the ways and
see and ask for the old pass where's the
good way and walked everything you shall
find rest for your souls very
interesting it's one of the only other
places that we find where Jesus besides
Jesus saying come unto me all you that
may ran are heavy maiden and I will give
you rest you will find rest for your
souls he's quoting from Jeremiah 6 16.
you shall find rest for your souls but
they said we will not walk therein also
I set Watchmen over you saying the heart
was at the side of the trumpet but they
said we will not hearken so Jesus is
quoting from Jeremiah 6 16 which says if
you walk in the Old Paths you will find
rest for your souls so one of the old
cats what is it that God wanted us to
walk in follow me go back to the screen
please notice with me please notice
Jeremiah 7 23 but this thing commanded
them saying obey my voice and I will be
your God and you shall be my people and
walk in all the ways that I I command
you that it may be well with you what
are the ways we're going to walk in
that's going to give us rest keeping the
Commandments of God how about Ezekiel 20
but the house of Israel rebelled against
me in the wilderness they walked not in
my statutes and they despise my
judgments which if a man do he shall
live in them and my Sabbath they greatly
polluted then I said I would part my
Fury upon them in the wilderness to
consume them but I wrote for my name's
sake that it shall not be polluted
before the Heathen in whose sight I
brought them out reading on yet also
would I lift my hand upon them the
Wilderness that I would not bring them
into the land which I have given them
formed with milk and honey which is the
glory of all lands because they despise
my judgments and walked not in my
statutes but colluded my sabbaths for
their hearts went after their idols
Chicago verse Ezekiel 36 verse 26 a new
heart also would I give you and a new
spirit what I put within you and I will
take away the Stony heart out of your
flesh and I will give you a heart of
Flesh and I will put my spirit within
you and cause you to walk in my statute
and you shall keep my judgment and do
them Beloved the very quote from which
the New Covenant is taken is the promise
that we will walk in the statutes of God
which is what he defines as rest
come on to me and I will give you rest
meaning what I will lead you to keep my
Commandments including the salad
now now
I think I got like four slides left bear
with me
buried
Isaiah 58
what is that all path very specifically
they best of me if they shall build the
old waste places thou shall raise up the
foundations of many generations thou
shall be called the repair of the breach
the restorer of paths to dwell in what
paths the old Palace if you keep the
Sabbath verse 13 if you turn away your
fruit from the south from doing thy
pleasure of my holy day and call the son
of a delight not a curse a delight not a
curse a delight not a doctrine of demons
a delight the holy of the Lord honorable
and shall honor him not to in thine own
ways nor finding that own pleasure nor
speaking that own word then shout out
the light thyself from the Lord and I
will cause you to ride upon the High
faces of the earth and feeding with the
heritage of Jacob by father from the
mouth of the Lord has spoken it stay on
the screen stay on the screen follow me
here
revelation 22 14 says this blessed are
they into his Commandments that they may
have right to the tree of life and they
enter in through the gates into the city
for without our dogs and Sorcerers at a
homeowners
under and this is a very solemn thing
I'm about to say and then we're praying
who are the dogs
who are the dogs that are outside the
scene let me show you
we're going to go back to Isaiah 56
verse 5.
notice that revelation 22 is almost
restating Isaiah 56 verse 5. in
revelation 22 those who keep the
Commandments enter into the city of God
those who don't are dogs and Sorcerers
and homeworkers watch Isaiah 56 5. even
unto them will I give in my house those
that keep the Sabbath
that's what Isaiah 56 is talking about
even unto them will I give in my house
and within my walls a place of name
better than Sons and Daughters I will
give them an everlasting name that shall
not be cut off also the sons of the
strangers that join themselves to the
Lord to serve him and to love the name
of the Lord to be his servants everyone
that keepeth the Sabbath from polluting
it and take a hold of my Covenant even
then when I bring into my Holy Mountain
revelation 22 y'all and make them joyful
In My House of Prayer they're burnt
offerings and their sacrifices will be
accepted upon my altar this is
symbolically speaking form on how
somebody called the house of prayer for
all people now watch this
same chapter
the Lord God will gap which gathered the
outcasts of Israel safe yet will I
gather others to him beside those that
are gathered unto him all ye Beasts of
the field come to devour yay all ye
beasts in the forest watch verse 10
y'all his Watchmen are blind they are
all ignorant they are all dumb dogs
they cannot bark
sleeping lying down loving to Slumber
yea they are greedy dogs which can never
have enough and they are Shepherds that
cannot understand
they all look to their own way everyone
for his game from his own quarter
ly saving I will fetch wine and we will
fit ourselves with strong drink and
tomorrow shall be is this day and much
more I need you to understand who the
dogs are
the dogs are those who are not
the dogs are those Watchmen
who are telling the flock it's all right
to not keep my Commandments
it's all right to break the Sabbath it's
all right to do your own thing the law
of God it doesn't stand anymore dumb
dogs blind Watchmen
many of us are listening and listen I
don't say this disrespectfully but many
of us are listening to people who do not
know what they are talking about
and by the grace of God many of those
people can be saved once they actually
come to an understanding but beloved
you've got to understand this
those who are against the Commandments
of God God calls them
the dogs
they're going to be outside the city
our opening verse and we're closing with
this verse let me read it again these
blind dogs are drinking wine
let's read our opening verse again
woe unto them that call evil good
and good evil
that put Darkness for light and light
for Darkness
that put bitter for sweet
and sweet for bitter woe unto them that
are wise in their own eyes and prudent
in their own sight woe unto them that
are Mighty to drink wine and Men of
strength to mingle strong drink which
justify the wicked for reward and take
away the righteousness of the righteous
from him
foreign
from this study
we have seen
that it is absolutely crystal clear
that the Sabbath
is not a part of the old Covenant that
was destroyed and waxed away in 70 A.D
the Sabbath is still God's sign between
him and his people regardless of
circumcision regardless of nationality
beloved
God is inviting you he's kidding he's
trying to give you a gift
why would we why would we take the gift
and rearrange not some other day of the
week or not it's no longer why would we
curse but God has blessed
listen to me I'm telling you
those who keep the Sabbath and I don't
mean just by going to church on the
seventh day of the week but I mean
actually living out the principle of the
South meaning I want you to sanctify me
Lord and recreate me in your image and
every seventh day will be a celebration
of what you've done for me not only
throughout that week but what you've
done for me since I became born again
it is our thank you to God
for creating us and delivering us out of
the bondage of sin
so I'm gonna make an appeal
my appeal is specifically for those of
you who have never kept us out
listen to me
you're not going to get to the Gates of
Heaven
and the Lord asked why did you rest on
the seventh day
because you know what you can easily say
I was just following Jesus example
Jesus didn't
it's a risk it is a risk
it is that's that's a big bet
to say I'm gonna try to get through the
gates and ignore one of these Ten
Commandments and when when it's told to
me that Jesus did it I'm gonna be like
well yeah but you know the early church
as far as I'm concerned you know they
didn't do it through my studies and I'm
just going to take my chances and I'm
not saying to do this out of fear y'all
that's not what I'm saying what I am
saying
is that always always go with what Jesus
did when in doubt do what Jesus did
Jesus kept it allocated to I don't tell
I would rather take my risk with Jesus
than my wrist with you telling me I
don't need to keep it because of your
understanding of what Paul said
so I'm going to invite you to put one in
the chat if you're if you have never
kept the Sabbath before or you've been
strung them with the Sabbath and maybe
you're not watching one here today but
but you're saying all right
I'm gonna give this a chance
I'm gonna give this a chance you don't
even need to put that one in the chat
you can make that decision between you
and God I don't need to see it right we
don't need to see it you might be
watching this afterwards you don't need
to put that one in the chat I need you
to just say in Your Heart Lord
all right
I'm gonna follow your way I'm going to
follow you
Heavenly Father
thank you for speaking to us
thank you for taking us on this study
through the word to show us
your will
to show us your Covenant
Lord we thank you
for revealing truth
and I pray Lord that those who will
watch us in the future will be convicted
in an overwhelming way
thank you Lord
Thank You For Truth
in Jesus name we pray amen
I want to invite you to uh the after
altar live uh we're going to put the
link up inside if you would like to join
us uh for the discussion on the Q a as
well as this sermon this Bible study
today please uh feel free to join us may
God bless you and um have a beautiful
rest of your Sabbath for those of you
who are keeping it and a beautiful rest
of your Sabbath for those of you who
have decided for the first time to keep
it God bless